Guide to the Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection, 1645–1969; Series I; 17.94; 41 boxes + 1 broadside.
  - Literary and Historical Manuscripts, 1688–1951
    - O'Brien, Mary, 1792–1813; 1873 (Box 41, Folder 935)
      Volume of letters, primarily by Mary (Palmer) O'Brien, Lady Inchiquin and Marchioness of Thomond. Correspondents include Joshua Reynolds Johnson, William Johnson, and Anna Maria Theresa (Tolley) Johnson. Includes an index of the letters.
    - O'Brien, Nelly, 1761 October 13 (Box 13, Folder 374)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from London, 3 pages. Accompanied by an engraving of O'Brien by Charles Spooner from the painting by Reynolds.
    - O'Neil, Henry, 1844 October 7 (Box 13, Folder 375)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Charles Lock Eastlake, from Rome, 2 pages.
    - Osborne, Francis, 5th Duke of Leeds, 1789 (Box 13, Folder 376)
      Five autograph letters, signed, to Augustus Henry Fitzroy, 3rd Duke of Grafton.
    - Osborne, Francis, 5th Duke of Leeds, 1771 February 17 (Box 13, Folder 377)
      Autograph letter, signed Carmathen, to Sir William Hamilton, from Florence, 3 pages.
    - Osborne, Francis, 5th Duke of Leeds, 1771–1773 (Box 13, Folder 378)
      Five autograph letters, signed Carmathen, to his father, Thomas Osborne.
    - Palmer, Barbara Villiers, Countess of Castlemaine and Duchess of Cleveland, undated (Box 13, Folder 379)
      Autograph letter to King Charles II, 1 page.
    - Paoli, Pasquale, undated (Box 13, Folder 380)
      Autograph document, signed, 1 leaf. Accompanied by an engraving of Paoli in Corsican military habit.
    - Papworth, J. B, 1840 May 9 (Box 13, Folder 381)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Morrison, 3 pages. Formerly laid in a volume labelled on spine "Fine Arts of the English School..." and not included on John Britton's list.
    - Parke, John, 1762 (Box 13, Folder 382)
      Bill of exchange authorizing the payment of £80, Liverpool. One of the endorsement signatures on the verso is that of William Cowper.
    - Parr, Samuel, 1807 July 23 (Box 13, Folder 383)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Chisholme, 1 page. Accompanied by an engraving of Parr by Ridley after the painting by Opie.
    - Parr, Samuel, 1804 July 30 (Box 13, Folder 384)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Richard Sharpe, 1 page.
    - Parr, Samuel, circa 1791; 1786–1796 (Box 13, Folder 385)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, 3 pages.
    - Peel, Sir Robert, 1842 March 15 (Box 14, Folder 386)
      Autograph letter, signed, to the Reverend Cotton, from London, 4 pages.
    - Percy, Thomas, 1782–1818; 1845–1846; undated (Box 33 (Oversize), Folder 905-915)
      A collection of letters primarily addressed to Thomas Percy, Bishop of Dromore, 1 volume. Contents include:
      Woodward, Richard, Bishop of Cloyne, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1787 September 23, Cloyne, 4 pages.
      Percy, Thomas, Letter in the hand of Percy's secretary, signed, to Robert Anderson, 1804 August 16, Dromore House, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1801 August 1, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1811 September 13, 3 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1800 September 13, 4 pages, including address.
      Woodward, Richard, Bishop of Cloyne, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1787 October 21, Cloyne, 3 pages.
      Woodward, Richard, Bishop of Cloyne, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1787 January 6, Dublin, 2 pages.
      Bennet, William, Bishop of Cloyne, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1802 July 24, Cloyne, 3 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1800 September 14, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      "Correspondence between Malone & Thomas Percy": manuscript listing owners of Percy/Malone letters, in an unidentified hand, undated, 1 page.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1790 December 23, Waterford, 2 pages.
      Bishop Percy: manuscript notes in an unidentified hand about Thomas Percy, 1793 July 2, 1 page.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1785 January 4, Dublin, 3 pages.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1783 March 29, Waterford, 3 pages, with address.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1782 July 29, Dublin, 4 pages, including address.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1787 June 24, Waterford, 4 pages.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1783 December 4, Dublin, 3 pages.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1787 April 30, Waterford, 3 pages.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1794 March 9, Waterford, 3 pages.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1784 March 19, Dublin, 4 pages.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1788 May 17, Mount Beresford, 3 pages.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1794 March 13, Waterford, 2 pages.
      Newcome, William, Bishop of Waterford, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1788 March 25, Dublin, 2 pages.
      Robinson, Richard, Archbishop of Armagh, Autograph letter, signed, (with initials) to Thomas Percy, 1783 May 3, London, 1 page, with address.
      Robinson, Richard, Archbishop of Armagh, Autograph letter, signed, (with initials) to Thomas Percy, 1787 May 2, Bath, 1 page, with address.
      Robinson, Richard, Archbishop of Armagh, Autograph letter, signed, (with initials) to Thomas Percy, 1782 March 30, 1 page, with address.
      Agar, Charles, Archbishop of Cashel, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1790 September 4, Cashel, 1 page, with address.
      Lodge, W., Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1800 November 17, Kilmore, 2 pages with address.
      Drummond, William Hamilton, Autograph letter (in the 3rd person) to Thomas Percy, 1809 December 23, Mount Collyer, Belfast, 1 page, with address.
      Drummond, William Hamilton, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1809 December 18, Mount Collyer, Belfast, 4 pages, including address.
      Hamilton, Hugh, Dean of Armagh, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1794 November 24, Armagh, 1 page, with address.
      Kearney, John, Bishop of Ossory, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1806 February 19, Dublin, 1 page, with address.
      Kearney, John, Bishop of Ossory, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1803 June 28, Dublin, 2 pages.
      Agar, Charles, Archbishop of Cashel, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1788 April 1, Stephens Green, 1 page, with address.
      Bennet, William, Bishop of Cloyne, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1802 April 30, Dublin, 2 pages, with address.
      Smith, William, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1805 June 3, Dublin, 2 pages, with address.
      Smith, William, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1805 March 4, Dublin. 4 pages.
      Drummond, William Hamilton Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1810 February 1, Mount Collyer, Belfast, 4 pages, including address.
      Drummond, William Hamilton Autograph letter (in the 3rd person) to Thomas Percy, 1810 February 14, Mount Collyer, Belfast, 2 pages, with address.
      Law, John, Bishop of Elphin, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1806 February 4, 1 page, with address.
      Smith, William, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1806 April 6, Downpatrick, 2 pages, with address.
      Barnard, Thomas, Bishop of Killaloe, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1782? March 30, St. Wolstans, 3 pages.
      Law, John, Bishop of Elphin, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1801 August 8, Elphin, 3 pages, with address.
      Smith, William, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1801? March 3, Downpatrick, 2 pages, with address.
      Smith, William, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1802 August 9, Armagh, 2 pages.
      Smith, William, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1805 April 12, 2 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to the Rev. Dr. Trail, 1801 December 7, Heriot's Green, 3 pages, with address.
      Smith, William, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1805 April 21, Downpatrick, 3 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1810 August 28, Kildress, 3 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1810 October 26, Kildress, 3 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1810 December 6, 4 pages, including address.
      "Inscription for a Mausoleum to the memory of Robert Bourne, Esq. Son of the Rev. Richard Bourne of Kildress, Ireland," undated, 1 page, printed.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1811 June 17, 1 page, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1805 September 3, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1805 April 12, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1805 April 9, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1805 April 3, Heriot's Green, 4 pages, including address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1799 July 31, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1811 June 22, 4 pages, including address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1806 July 13, Heriot's Green, 8 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1806 August 14, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Robinson, 1806 October 30, Heriot's Green, 3 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1806 November 18, Heriot's Green, 4 pages, including address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1806 December 8, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Erskine, David Steuart, 11th Earl of Buchan, "The Four Repasts of the Day." Unpublished pamphlet, undated, 6 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, "List of Old Scottish Songs": autograph manuscript list made for the Bishop of Dromore, 1800 December 29, Edinburgh, 8 pages.
      Obituary of Mrs. Percy: manuscript notes in an unidentified hand containing the account of Mrs. Percy's death, in the Gentleman's Magazine, 1807, 1 page.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1807 March 11, Heriot's Green, 4 pages, including address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1807 April 23, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1807 July 23, Heriot's Green, 9 pages.
      Percy, Thomas, Autograph letter (in the 3rd person; in the hand of his secretary; incomplete) to Robert Anderson, 1808 January 4, Dromore House, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1808 August 18, Heriot's Green, 8 pages.
      Obituary of Thomas Percy's Nephew: manuscript notes, in an unidentified hand, containing the account of the death of the Rev. Thomas Percy LL.D, in the Gentleman's Magazine, 1808, 1 page.
      Percy, Thomas, Autograph letter (in the 3rd person; in the hand of his secretary) to Robert Anderson, 1808 May 24, Dromore, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1808 July 14, Heriot's Green, 4 pages, including address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1808 August 26, Heriot's Green, 4 pages, including address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1808 November 15, Heriot's Green, 3 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1809 April 28, Heriot's Green, 4 pages, including address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1818 December 6, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1809 May 12, Belfast, 2 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1809 June 6, Kildress, 3 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, undated, 1 page, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, (incomplete) to Thomas Percy, 1804 October 29, 5 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1811 August 17, 4 pages.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. M. Durby, 1811 October 9, 3 pages, with address.
      Anderson, Robert, Autograph letter to Thomas Percy, 1803 August 16, Heriot's Green, 4 pages.
      Trumbull, W. B. D. D., Autograph letter, signed, to John Bowyer Nichols, 1847? January 22, Edinburgh, 2 pages.
      Unidentified, Autograph letter, signed, to John Bowyer Nichols, undated, Friday, 2 pages, with envelope.
      "Desiderata": manuscript notes in an unidentified hand, undated, 1 page.
      Trumbull, W. B. D. D., Autograph letter, signed, to John Bowyer Nichols, 1846 November 17, Edinburgh, 3 pages.
      Nichols, John Bowyer, Autograph letter, signed, (with initials) to W. B. D. D. Trumbull, 1846 November 28, 1 page. On verso: Stephenson, Edward, Autograph letter, signed, (partly printed) to John Bowyer Nichols, 1845 August 8, London, 1 page.
      Nichols, John Bowyer, Autograph letter, signed, (with initials) to W. B. D. D ? Trumbull, 1846 November 16, 1 page.
    - Percy, Thomas, 1777 October 12 (Box 14, Folder 387)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Easton Manduit, 4 pages.
    - Percy, Thomas, 1797 September 6 (Box 14, Folder 388)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Messrs. Cadell and Davies, from Near Northampton, 3 pages.
    - Percy, Thomas, 1771 April 14 (Box 14, Folder 389)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Professor Chambers, from Northumberland House, 1 page.
    - Pickersgill, Frederick Richard, 1843 July 14 (Box 14, Folder 390)
    - Pilkington, Mary, undated (Box 14, Folder 391)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to the editor of the Lady's Museum, from Brook Green, 2 pages. Accompanied by an engraving of Pilkington.
    - Ponsonby, William Brabazon, 1st Baron Ponsonby, 1789 March (Box 14, Folder 392)
      Three autograph letters, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Richard Brinsley Sheridan.
    - Ponsonby, William Brabazon, 1st Baron Ponsonby, 1789 March 27 (Box 14, Folder 393)
      Manuscript letter, signed, possibly in the hand of an amanuensis, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Richard Brinsley Sheridan, from Dublin, 1 page.
    - Pope, Alexander, 1734 December (Box 14, Folder 394)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Fortescue, from London, 1 page.
    - Pope, Alexander, undated (Box 14, Folder 395)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Jonathan Richardson, 1 page.
    - Porter, Jane, undated (Box 14, Folder 396)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Mrs. Reynolds, 2 pages.
    - Pratt, Samuel Jackson, 1786–1805; undated (Box 14, Folder 397)
      Nine autograph letters, signed, and four fragments of autograph letters to John Fonblanque. Accompanied by an engraving of Pratt by Caroline Watson from a painting by Mr. Lawrence.
    - Pratt, Samuel Jackson, circa 1806?; 1801–1811 (Box 14, Folder 398)
      Manuscript letter, written in an unidentified hand, to Mr. Hill, from Bury St. Edmunds, 2 pages.
    - Pratt, Samuel Jackson, undated (Box 14, Folder 399)
      Autograph letter, signed Courtney Melmoth, to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, 2 pages.
    - Pratt, Samuel Jackson, 1811 December 14 (Box 14, Folder 400)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Sterndale, from Newport, 2 pages.
    - Pringle, Sir John, 1766 September 6 (Box 14, Folder 401)
    - Psalmanazaar, George, 1706 October 18 (Box 14, Folder 402)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Samuel Reynolds, from London, 3 pages.
    - Pusey, Edward Bouverie, ? May 4 (Box 14, Folder 403)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Oxford, 1 page.
    - Pusey, Edward Bouverie, 1860 June 21 (Box 14, Folder 404)
      Fragment of an autograph letter, signed, to Francis Martin, from Oxford, 2 pages.
    - Reynolds family, undated (Box 32 (Oversize), Folder 891)
      A sheet containing the following manuscript material:
      1. A leaf with the autograph of Samuel Reynolds
      2. A leaf from a pocket-book of Sir Joshua Reynolds
      3. Three autographs of Sir Joshua Reynolds
      4. Autograph of Frances Reynolds
      5. Autograph of Mary Palmer O'Brien, Marchioness of Thomond
      6. Autograph of Theophila Palmer
    - Reynolds family, undated (Box 32 (Oversize), Folder 892)
      Reynolds and the Johnson circle drawing, in an unidentified hand.
    - Reynolds, Frances, 1801 July 8 (Box 14, Folder 405)
      Autograph letter, signed, to a niece, 4 pages.
    - Reynolds, Francis, 1761 July 5 (Box 14, Folder 406)
      Autograph, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1786 August (Box 14, Folder 407)
      Autograph manuscript bill of £367.10 for four paintings done for the Earl of Thanet, 1 page, endorsed on the verso.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, ? April 28 (Box 14, Folder 408)
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, undated (Box 14, Folder 409)
      Letter, written in the third person in an unidentified hand, to Mr. Burney, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1779 March 29 (Box 14, Folder 410)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Thomas Cadell, from London, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1789? February 6; 1789 February 6 (Box 14, Folder 411)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Sir William Chambers, 2 pages.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1790 or 1791? May 17; 1790–1791; 1823 September 10 (Box 15, Folder 412)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to George Coleman, 1 page. Accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, from George Coleman to an unidentified recipient, 1823 September 10, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1789 December 24 (Box 15, Folder 413)
      Autograph letter, written in the hand of Mary Palmer, to Dr. Farr, from London, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1784 April 8 (Box 15, Folder 414)
      Manuscript letter, written in an unidentified hand, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Stephen Fuller, from London, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1778 April 24 (Box 15, Folder 415)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Gawlor, 2 pages.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1785 January (Box 15, Folder 416)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Mary Hamilton, from London, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1770 June 17 (Box 15, Folder 417)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Sir William Hamilton, from London, 3 pages. Bound in tan straight-grain morocco gilt with engraving of Reynolds by Collyer.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, ? February 20 (Box 15, Folder 418)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to William Hodges, 1 page. Accompanied by an engraving of Reynolds by J. Cochran.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, circa 1775 September 24 (Box 15, Folder 419)
      Letter, written in the third person in the hand of Frances Reynolds, to Ozias Humphry, from London, 1 page. Mounted on a sheet with a note by W. Upcott and a copy of a poem about Sir Joshua.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1779 February 24 (Box 15, Folder 420)
      Letter, written in the third person, possibly in the hand of Frances Reynolds, to George Michael Moser, 1 page. Includes a pen and ink sketch of man holding a trowel on the verso.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1790 February 6 (Box 15, Folder 421)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Nichols, from London, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1790 May 24 (Box 15, Folder 422)
      Letter, written in the third person in the hand of Mary Palmer, to James Northcote, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1790 December 18 (Box 15, Folder 423)
      Manuscript copy, written in an unidentified hand, of a letter to Mrs. Robinson, from London, 2 pages.
    - Reynolds, Sir Joshua, 1775 August 9 (Box 15, Folder 424)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Thrale, from London, 1 page.
    - Reynolds, Robert, 1773 October 9 (Box 15, Folder 425)
      Bill of exchange authorizing the payment of ten pounds to William Floyd. Sent to Sir Joshua Reynolds and signed by him, 1 page, endorsed on the verso.
    - Reynolds, Samuel, 1702 or 1703; 1702–1703; 1737 September 5 (Box 15, Folder 426)
      Manuscript note, signed, on a leaf from a duodecimo edition of selected letters from Balzac. Includes the signature of Sir Joshua Reynolds on the recto and verso. Accompanied by a photocopy of an autograph letter, signed, to Courtenay Croker, from Plymton, 3 pages.
    - Richards, John Inigo, 1801 November 26 (Box 15, Folder 427)
      Autograph letter, written in the 3rd person, to Benjamin West, from London, 1 page.
    - Richards, John Inigo, 1809 July 4 (Box 15, Folder 428)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Messrs. Cadell and Davies, from London, 1 page.
    - Richardson, J. D., 1782 March 30 (Box 15, Folder 429)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, from Maorca, 3 pages.
    - Richardson, Samuel, 1753 June 12 (Box 15, Folder 430)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Elizabeth Carter, 4 pages. Accompanied by an engraving of Richardson.
    - Richardson, Samuel, 1749 or 1750 January 22; 1749–1750 (Box 15, Folder 431)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Frances Granger, 6 pages.
    - Richardson, Samuel, 1754?; 1754 (Box 15, Folder 432)
      Fragment of an autograph letter, signed, to Benjamin Kennicott, 1 leaf. Accompanied by a clipping about Pamela.
    - Richardson, Samuel, 1758 November 9 (Box 15, Folder 433)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Barbara Montagu, from London, 2 pages.
    - Richmond, George, 1873 February 16 (Box 16, Folder 434)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Elizabeth Eastlake, from London, 1 page.
    - Rivarol, Antoine, comte de, 1828 May 9 (Box 16, Folder 435)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Paris, 1 page.
    - Rivarol, Antoine, comte de, 1841 August 24 (Box 16, Folder 436)
      Autograph letter, signed, to the Minister of Public Instruction, from Seine et Marne, 3 pages.
    - Rivarol, Antoine, comte de, 1757-1801, 1801 March 10 (Box 16, Folder 437)
      Autograph letter, signed with a signature affixed from another letter, to Monsieur Justel, from Berlin, 3 pages. Accompanied by an English translation, 4 leaves.
    - Rivarol, Louise-Mather Flint, comtesse de, 1795–1796 (Box 16, Folder 438)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to an unidentified recipient.
    - Rivarol, Louise-Mather Flint, comtesse de, 1793 October 29 (Box 16, Folder 439)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lavoisier? 1793 Oct 29, Paris? 3 pages, with address
    - Rivarol, Louise-Mather Flint, comtesse de, 1800–1820 (Box 16, Folder 440)
      Five autograph letters, signed, to the Ministre de l'Intérieur, Lucien Bonaparte.
    - Roberts, David, undated (Box 16, Folder 441)
    - Robinson, Sir William, 1784 May 22 (Box 16, Folder 442)